<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
        <metadata>
                <title></title>
        </metadata>

<section>
        <title>Dialog Windows</title>
<p>
Many of the dialog windows have multiple pages of information and are
controlled in a consistent fashion.  Press the '$>>$' button to select
the next page of the dialog, and the 'OK' button do make the dialog
disappear.
</p>

<section>
	<title>Waypoint Details</title>
<p>
Several ways of selecting a waypoint are available:
</p>

<ul>
<li> Touch its name or the waypoint symbol on the map screen if it is
visible.</li>
<li> If the waypoint is in the active task, highlight the waypoint InfoBox, then use the up/down arrow keys to select the desired waypoint, and press the
enter key.</li>
<li> From the Task dialog, find and highlight the waypoint in
 the waypoint list, then press the 'Details' button.</li>
</ul>
<p>
The display will now show the waypoint details dialog.
</p>

<p>
The waypoint details dialog contains several pages:
</p>

<dl>
	<dt>
		Waypoint details
	</dt>
	<dd>
		This page contains text describing the waypoint's location, elevation
		and local sunset.  For airfields, the page may also include relevant
		text from the Enroute Supplement about the airfield, including
		runways, radio frequencies, traffic patterns, contacts.
	</dd>

<!-- XXX get eps (other format...
\begin{center}
\includegraphics[angle=0,width=0.8\linewidth,keepaspectratio='true']{../quick/fig-wpersa.eps}

{\it DIAGRAM SHOWING WAYPOINT DETAILS ERSA PAGE}
-->

	<dt>
		Task menu
	</dt>
	<dd>
		This page contains a menu of buttons allowing various actions to be performed:
		<ul>
			<li> Goto direct: cancels the current task and sets the waypoint as the
			  single active waypoint in the task.</li>
			<li> Replace active: replaces the active waypoint in the task.</li>
			<li> Insert here: inserts the waypoint before the active waypoint in
			  the task.</li>
			<li> Remove: removes the waypoint from the task.</li>
			<li> Set home: sets the waypoint as the home airfield</li>
		</ul>
	</dd>

	<dt>
		Satellite image 
	</dt>
	<dd>
		This page shows a satellite image of the waypoint.
	</dd>

		<!-- XXX image !
		\includegraphics[angle=0,width=0.8\linewidth,keepaspectratio='true']{../quick/fig-wpmodis.eps}
		{\it DIAGRAM SHOWING WAYPOINT DETAILS SATELLITE PAGE}
		-->

</dl>

Depending on the configuration files specified in the settings, not
all of these pages may be available.

</section>

<section>
	<title>Analysis</title>

<p>
To activate the analysis dialog, select the 'Analysis' option from the
main menu.
</p>

<p>
The analysis dialog contains several pages:
</p>

<dl>

	<dt>
		Barograph
	</dt>
	<dd>
		Shows a graph of the history of the altitude of the glider.
		Statistics are used to estimate the thermal working band (average
		base and ceiling of climbs) and to estimate how the ceiling is
		changing over time.  The base and ceiling lines are drawn on the
		barograph.
	</dd>

	<!-- XXX Diagram
		{\it DIAGRAM SHOWING ANALYSIS BAROGRAPH PAGE}
	-->


	<dt>
		Climb history
	</dt>
	<dd>
		Shows a bar chart of the average climb rate acheived during each
		climb.  Statistics are used to estimate the overall average climb
		rate, and to estimate how this average is changing over time.  The
		current MacCready setting is drawn on the bar chart as a thick red
		dashed line, and the climb rate trend is drawn on the chart as a
		black line.
		<!-- XXX Diagram
		{\it DIAGRAM SHOWING ANALYSIS BAROGRAPH PAGE}
		-->
	</dd>


	<dt>
		Wind at altitude
	</dt>
	<dd>
		This shows a graph of the wind magnitude versus height, and shows the
		wind vector at several heights.
	</dd>

<!-- XXX
{\it DIAGRAM SHOWING ANALYSIS WIND AT ALTITUDE PAGE}
-->

	<dt>
		Glide polar
	</dt>
	<dd>
		This shows a graph of the glide polar at the current bugs and ballast
		setting.  It also shows the calculated best LD and the speed at which 
		it occurs, and the minumum sink and the speed at which it occurs.
	</dd>

<!-- XXX
{\it DIAGRAM SHOWING ANALYSIS GLIDE POLAR PAGE}
-->

	<dt>
		Temperature trace
	</dt>
	<dd>
		This page is only available if a supported instrument is connected
		to XCSoar that produces outside air temperature and humidity.  The
		chart shows the variation of dry air temperature, dew point
		temperature and outside air temperature with height.  The convection
		forecast is summarised as the estimated thermal convection height
		and estimated cloud base.
	</dd>

<!-- XXX
{\it DIAGRAM SHOWING ANALYSIS TEMP TRACE PAGE}
-->

</dl>

</section>

<section>
<title>Status</title>

The status dialog is a single page of text summarising the status of
the aircraft, task, and connected devices, including:
<ul>
<li> The glider's latitude and longitude and altitude</li>
<li> Sunset expressed in local time zone</li>
<li> Range and bearing to the nearest landmark</li>
<li> GPS status and number of satellites in view</li>
<li> Logger status</li>
</ul>

<!-- 
XXX ?? anything else, FLARM, PDA battery, glider battery?
-->

<!-- XXX Diagram
{\it DIAGRAM SHOWING STATUS DIALOG}
-->

</section>

<section>
<title>Bugs and ballast</title>

<p>
	Use the Bugs/Ballast dialog to modify the polar of the glider both
	before and during flight.  The bugs settings determines the amount the
	polar is degraded due to contamination during a long flight.  A bugs
	setting of 100\% will cause the software to use the clean polar. A
	bugs setting of 50\% will degrade the polar by 50\%, effectively
	doubling the sink rate.
</p>

<p>
	The ballast setting is used to modify the polar to account for any
	water ballast carried during the flight. A ballast setting of 100\%
	modifies the polar to account for a full load of water ballast.  
</p>

<!-- XXX Find diagram 
{\it DIAGRAM SHOWING BUGS AND BALLAST DIALOG}
-->

</section>

<section>
	<title>Pressure</title>

<p>
	Use this dialog both before and during the flight to record the mean
	sea level atmospheric pressure, also known as QNH pressure.  The
	software uses the values entered to convert airspace flight levels
	into altitudes.
</p>

<!-- XXX Find diagram 
{\it DIAGRAM SHOWING PRESSURE DIALOG}
-->
</section>

</section>
</document>
