<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
        <metadata>
                <title>Setup</title>
        </metadata>


		<section>
			<title>Hardware Button</title>
			<p>
			It is a good idea to assign one of your PocketPC hardware buttons to
			run XCSoar. See your PocketPC manual for details of how to do this.
			</p>

			<p>
			Owners of Compaq Aero PocketPCs may find it useful to enable `Game
			Keys'.
			</p>
		</section>

		<section>
			<title>Updates</title>
			<p>
			You should periodically visit the XCSoar website to check for program
			updates.  The installation procedure described above can typically be
			repeated in order to upgrade the software.  All user configuration
			settings and data files will be preserved during the
			re-installation/upgrade.
			</p>

			<p>
			It is also recommended to periodically check for updates to data
			files, particularly Special Use Airspace, which may be subject to
			change by the national aviation authority.
			</p>

			<p>
			Like any complex software program, XCSoar may be subject to software
			bugs, so if you find any, please report them to the XCSoar developers.
			</p>
		</section>

		<section>
			<title>Running</title>
			<p>
			The program can be run in either of two modes by pressing the 'FLY' or
			'SIM' launcher on the Today screen:
			<ul>
				<li>[FLY] This mode is used when actually flying.  The simulator is 
				  disabled and serial communications are active. </li>
				<li>[SIM] This starts XCSoar in simulator mode, no serial communications
				  are attempted.</li>
			</ul>
			</p>

			<p>
			In addition to starting the program by the use of the launcher, it is
			also possible to use the File Explorer to locate the
			XCSoar.exe or XCSoarSimulator.exe programs 
			(respectively FLY and SIM modes).  Typically these are located in the
			\Program Files\XCSoar directory.
			</p>

			<p>
			You can also execute XCSoar and XCSoar Simulator from
			the Start Menu or in Start Programs (depending on your configuration)
			</p>

			<!--
			XXX Describe somewhere how the simulator works...
			-->
		</section>


		<section>
			<title>Using XCSoar with a flight simulator</title>

			<p>
			A good way to learn how to use XCSoar is to connect the Pocket PC
			device to a PC running a flight simulator that can output NMEA
			sentances to the serial port.  Suitable simulators include Condor and
			X-Plane.  
			</p>

			<p>
			The benefit of this form of training is that XCSoar can be used in FLY
			mode, so it behaves exactly as if you were really flying, and you can
			get a good feel for how the program works while you are flying the
			simulator.
			</p>
		</section>
</document>

