<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
        <metadata>
                <title>GPS</title>
        </metadata>

		<section>
		<title>GPS</title>

<p>
The GPS is the most important part of XCSoar hardware (apart from the <a
href="../organiser/">organiser</a>
itself). The GPS can come in many forms and most of them can be used by XCSoar.
</p>

<p>
Almost all GPS units provide a serial output standard <a
href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NMEA">NMEA</a> signal. Almost all
<a href="../organiser/">Organisers</a> provide a serial port, usually by purchasing another cable.
In theory any GPS capable of serial or bluetooth that can output NMEA should
work, once you have the right cable and settings.
</p>

<p>
Some <a href="../organiser/">Organisers</a> have built in GPS units and you can
also get Compact Flash and Secure Digital versions.
</p>

<p>
Alternatively there is also <a
href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bluetooth">Bluetooth</a> input to organisers, and many new models
of GPS provide <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bluetooth">Bluetooth</a> connections.
</p>

<p>
Some of the GPS units we will talk about are often referred to as 'Chip sets'.
This is because technically they are made by one manufacturer but are often
rebadged and repackged by many companies. There is often too many of these to
list.
</p>

</section>

<section>
<title>Some GPS Units Available</title>
<ul>
	<li>Garmin</li>
	<li>Magellan</li>
	<li>Volkslogger</li>
	<li>FLARM</li>
	<li>Cambridge Varios/Computers</li>


</ul>

<section>
<title>Garmin</title>
<p>
<a href="http://www.garmin.com/">Garmin</a> GPS receivers have been around a long time and in the early days made
were a big part in the promotion of the NMEA in serial ports. 
</p>
<p>
Unfortunately the bad news for the future of Garmin is that they are
dropping support for NMEA and <a
href="http://www.oreillynet.com/pub/wlg/5745">going more proprietary</a>.
PVT is an alternative format, which would in theory be fine for support in XCS,
except that it does not allow the interlacing of other existing NMEA strings
(such as those from <a href="../varios/">Varios</a>).
</p>
<p>
To use a Garmin you need a Garmin Serial and Power cable, probably a null-modem adapter and a
serial cable to suit your organiser. You also need to make sure the settings of
your Garmin interface is NMEA Out (refer to your Garmin manual - or google).
</p>

</section>

<section>
<title>Magellan</title>
<p>
In the early days, if you din't have a Garmin then you had a <a
href="http://www.magellangps.com/">Magellan</a>.
</p>

</section>

<section>
<title>Volkslogger</title>
<p>
For those world record attempts, it is a good idea to have an <a
href="http://www.fai.org/gliding/">IGC</a> approvded logger. It just so happens
that the <a href="http://www.volkslogger.de/">Volkslogger</a> also outputs the NMEA GPS stream which can be used in
XCSoar.
</p>
</section>

<section>
<title>FLARM</title>
<p>
Safety is an important aspect of our sport. <a
href="http://www.flarm.com/">FLARM</a> has made an excellent collision
avoidance system that can be used also as a stream of NMEA data for XCSoar.
</p>
</section>

<section>
<title>Cambridge Varios and Computers</title>

<p><a href="http://www.cambridge-aero.com/">Cambridge</a> models 10, 20 &amp; 25
and computer 302 support GPS NMEA output which can be used by XCSoar.
</p>

</section>

<section>
<title>Other GPS Units</title>

<p>Mouse... (asus ?) </p>


</section>

<section>
<title>Compact Flash GPS Units</title>

</section>

<section>
<title>Secure Digital GPS Units</title>

<p>Globalsat ?</p>
</section>

<section>
<title>Bluetooth GPS Units</title>
<p>BT338, SIRF Star III ...</p>
</section>

<section>
<title>Other resources and links</title>
<ul>

	<li><a href="http://www.lxnavigation.si/">LX Navigation</a></li>
	<li><a href="http://www.filser.de/">Filser</a></li>
	<li><a href="http://www.trautenberg.net/">Hans Trautenberg</a> - garmin
cables and more</li>
	<li><a href="http://www.soarmn.com/cumulus/goddard.htm#Cable_Selection_Guide">Cumulus Soaring</a> - data cable selection guide</li>
</ul>
</section>


</section>

</document>
