<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
        <metadata>
                <title>Map</title>
        </metadata>

<section>
        <title>Map area</title>

<!-- XXX IMAGE
\begin{center}
\includegraphics[angle=0,width=\linewidth,keepaspectratio='true']{../quick/fig-map.eps}

{\it DIAGRAM SHOWING BASIC MAP AREA WITH ALL LAYERS DESCRIBED BELOW
(LABELED), NO INFOBOXES, NO BUTTON LABELS, NO MENU}
-->

<p>
The moving map shows:
</p>

<ul>
<li> Glider symbol</li>
<li> Waypoints</li>
<li> The active task</li>
<li> The bearing to the next waypoint</li>
<li> Special Use Airspace</li>
<li> Terrain and topology</li>
<li> Markers</li>
<li> Trail</li>
<li> Glide range</li>
</ul>

<p>
The map is drawn in a projected coordinate system (not latitude and
longitude), and can be zoomed in and out, changing the scale, as well
as panned.
</p>

</section>

<section>
	<title>Map scale</title>

<p>
To change the scale of the map:
</p>

<ul>
	<li> Tap on a blank part of the map to highlight the map if it is not already
	selected.</li>
	<li> Then use the PocketPC up/down key to either zoom in or out.</li>
</ul>

<p>
The map scale is displayed in the lower left corner of the moving map
display, and as a striped bar on the right side of the map area.  The
alternating colors in the striped bar represent the distance
measurement in a decimal scale, (e.g.\ 0.1 km, 1 km, 10 km, 100 km)
depending on the zoom level.
</p>

<p>
Compaq Aero Users. If you enable the Compaq Aero Game Keys (On the
Q-menu) the centre two front buttons become the up/down keys.
</p>

<p>
There is a facility to have two zoom settings; one when the glider is
in circling flight mode, and one in the cruise or final glide flight
mode.  This is the "Circling zoom" option in the Settings-$>$Display.
By default, the cruise/final glide zoom is 5 km and 0.3 km for
circling.  When the user zooms in or out, it affects the current
mode's zoom setting only, so when leaving the mode the previous mode's
zoom setting is used.  If ``Circling Zoom'' is not enabled, there is
only a single zoom level.
</p>

<p>
Auto-zoom automatically zooms in when approaching a waypoint to keep
the waypoint at a reasonable screen distance.  The user can still zoom
out if desired.  When auto-zoom is active, an 'A' appears next to the
map scale.  
</p>

<p>
When a waypoint changes (automatically, via the task selector, or by
manually switching waypoints), autozoom returns the zoom level to what
it was immediately prior to any automatic zooming in it may have
performed.  This has the effect of allowing users to zoom in and out
manually in cruise, and when approaching a waypoint, the system
automatically zooms in.  When passing the waypoint, the system goes
back to the previous cruise zoom level in effect.
</p>

<!-- XXX Images
\includegraphics[angle=0,width=0.2\linewidth,keepaspectratio='true']{cut-mapscale.eps}
{\it DIAGRAM SHOWING MAP SCALE AND AUTOZOOM SYMBOL (CUTOUT OF MAIN MAPAREA)}
\end{center}
{\it DIAGRAM SHOWING HOW AUTOZOOM WORKS AS YOU APPROACH AND PASS A WAYPOINT}
-->

</section>

<section>
	<title>Panning the map</title>
<p>
A pan mode allows the user to explore areas beyond the glider.  This
is particularly useful when task planning.
</p>

<ul>
<li> Enable pan mode by pressing the XXX hardware or onscreen button.</li>
<li> The map can then be panned by dragging the screen or using the cursor
  keys.</li>
<li> When done, pan mode should be disabled by pressing the XXX hardware or
onscreen button.</li>
</ul>

<p>
When pan is active, the text 'PAN' appears next to the map scale.  The
location of focus when panning moves with the glider.
</p>

<!-- XXX image
\begin{center}
%\includegraphics[angle=0,width=\linewidth,keepaspectratio='true']{../quick/fig-task.eps}
{\it DIAGRAM SHOWING PANNED DISPLAY AND LABELED ARROW TO PAN SYMBOL,
  FULLSCREEN}
-->

</section>

<section>
	<title>Glider symbol, map orientation</title>

<p>
The glider symbol shows the position of the glider on the map.  The
orientation of the glider indicates the estimated heading of the
glider.
</p>

<p>
The map is oriented in one of two ways, depending on the flight mode
and the configuration settings:
</p>

<dl>
	<dt>North up</dt>
	<dd>
		Here the map is always oriented with true north up.
		The glider symbol is rotated according to its track corrected for wind.
	</dd>

	<dt>Track-up</dt>
	<dd>
	 Here the map is oriented so that the glider's track
	  made good is up.  The north arrow symbol points to true north.  
	  The glider symbol may be shown rotated according to the computed
	  heading of the glider taking wind into account.
	</dd>
</dl>

<!-- XXX Image
%\includegraphics[angle=0,width=\linewidth,keepaspectratio='true']{../quick/fig-task.eps}

{\it DIAGRAM SHOWING SCREEN ORIENTATIONS AND LABELED ARROW TO NORTH ARROW,
  FULLSCREEN}
-->

<p>
Configuration settings can be used to further specify north or
track-up when in circling mode.  These are useful to prevent
disorientation when looking at the map while circling.  Track-up when
circling makes it easy to determine which direction to exit the
thermal.
</p>

</section>


<section>
	<title>Waypoints</title>

<p>
Waypoints are displayed with different symbols depending on the
waypoint type.  Those marked as landing points in the database file are
drawn as a filled circle. All other types of waypoint are drawn as a
small black hollow circle.   
</p>

<!-- Image
\includegraphics[angle=0,width=0.4\linewidth,keepaspectratio='true']{cut-waypoints.eps}
{\it DIAGRAM SHOWING DIFFERENT WAYPOINT SYMBOLS ON A MAP: NORMAL WAYPOINTS, 
 LANDABLE AIRFIELDS, REACHABLE LANDABLE AIRFIELDS.  FULLSCREEN, NO TASK}
-->
<p>
XCSoar continually calculates which landing points are with in gliding
range using the current wind and MacCready settings.
</p>

<p>
The waypoint symbols are shown below:
</p>

<ul>
<li> Non-landable waypoint</li>
<li> Unreachable airfields are purple filled circles  </li>
<li> Reachable airfields in purple filled circles with a green band</li>
</ul>

<p>
The estimated arrival altitude of landable points is optionally
displayed next to the waypoint.
</p>

<p>
At large zoom scales, all waypoints are drawn as small black crosses.
</p>

<p>
Waypoints are optionally labelled, in a regular font.
</p>

</section>


<section>
	<title>Active task</title>
<p>
The active task course is drawn on the map as a green dashed line.
Assigned area tasks also show the task sectors or areas as a shaded
region.  The start and finish waypoint additionally show green circles
or lines representing the start and finish zones or lines.  Task
observation sectors are drawn as green segments.
</p>

<p>
At all times a thick black line is drawn from the glider to the next
waypoint in the task.
</p>

<!-- XXX image
\includegraphics[angle=0,width=\linewidth,keepaspectratio='true']{../quick/fig-task.eps}

{\it SEVERAL DIAGRAM CUTOUTS SHOWING (1) TASK LINES (ZOOMED OUT), (2)
START ZONE, (3) TURNPOINT SECTORS (4) AAT AREAS (5) FINISH
ZONE. FULLSCREEN, NO INFOBOXES, NO TERRAIN OR TOPOLOGY}

\includegraphics[angle=0,width=0.3\linewidth,keepaspectratio='true']{cut-startfinish.eps} 
\includegraphics[angle=0,width=0.3\linewidth,keepaspectratio='true']{cut-sector.eps} 
\includegraphics[angle=0,width=0.3\linewidth,keepaspectratio='true']{cut-barrel.eps}
-->

</section>

<section>
	<title>Special Use Airspace</title>

<p>
Local special use airspace regions are drawn on the map as shaded
areas.  The color and pattern of the areas are specific to different
airspace categories and may be configured by the user.  Depending on
the settings, the user may choose to display no airspace, only
airspace above, only airspace within a particular height separation,
or automatic display where XCSoar decides when it is important to
display the regions.
</p>

<!-- XXX Images
\includegraphics[angle=0,width=0.4\linewidth,keepaspectratio='true']{cut-airspace.eps}
{\it DIAGRAM SHOWING MULTIPLE AIRSPACE REGIONS WITH DIFFERENT COLORS,
PATTERNS.  FULLSCREEN, NO INFOBOXES, NO TERRAIN OR TOPOLOGY}
-->

</section>

<section>
	<title>Terrain and Topology</title>

The following topological features are drawn on the map:
<ul>
<li> Major roads, shown as red lines</li>
<li> Rivers, shown as blue lines</li>
<li> Large water bodies (lakes), shown as blue areas</li>
<li> Large cities, shown as yellow areas</li>
<li> Small population areas, shown as yellow diamonds</li>
</ul>

<p>
Cities and small population areas are labeled in italics.
</p>

<p>
Terrain is colored according to height, and optionally shaded by sun
direction or lift-generating slope.  Invalid terrain, or terrain below
sea level is colored blue.
</p>

<p>
Terrain is phong-shaded to improve visibility.  Currently the shading
is set up so that the virtual lighting position is the wind bearing,
thus brighter areas are on the upwind side of hills and dark areas in
the lee of the hill.  Support for a sun ephemeris is underway.
</p>

<p>
Both terrain and topology display can be switched on or off by
pressing a button.
</p>

<!-- XXX image
\includegraphics[angle=0,width=0.4\linewidth,keepaspectratio='true']{cut-topo.eps} \includegraphics[angle=0,width=0.4\linewidth,keepaspectratio='true']{cut-terrain.eps}
{\it DIAGRAMS SHOWING TOPOLOGY AND TERRAIN, SHADING. FULLSCREEN, NO TASK}
-->

</section>

<section>
	<title>Trail</title>

<p>
An optional 'snail trail' is drawn on the map showing the glider's
path history.  The color and thickness of the trail depends on the
variometer value; with lift areas being presented in green and thicker
lines, sink areas being presented in red with thin lines.  Zero lift
is presented as a grey line.
</p>

<!-- XXX Image
\includegraphics[angle=0,width=0.8\linewidth,keepaspectratio='true']{../quick/fig-snail.eps}
{\it DIAGRAM CUTOUT SHOWING SNAIL TRAIL COLORS AND THICKNESS IN LIFT AND SINK.
  FULLSCREEN, NO TOPOLOGY OR TERRAIN.}
-->

<p>
If an intelligent variometer is connected with Netto output, the Netto
vario value is used; hence the colors and thickness of the trail
indicates the airmass vertical movement rather than that of the
glider.
</p>

<p>
The snail trail display can be toggled off, a short trail (about ten
minutes) or a long trail (about one hour).
</p>

</section>

<section>
	<title>Markers</title>

<p>
Markers are shown as small flags on the map.  The markers can be dropped
manually, by pressing a button, or automatically.  An example use of
automatic markers is to drop markers when entering circling mode, as a
simple way of showing all thermals encountered.
</p>

<p>
Markers are not preserved after XCSoar is exited, however the location
of all marks are saved to the file \verb|xcsoar-marks.txt|.
</p>

<!-- XXX IMAGE
%\includegraphics[angle=0,width=0.8\linewidth,keepaspectratio='true']{../quick/fig-snail.eps}
{\it DIAGRAM CUTOUT SHOWING MARKERS ON A MAP WITH SNAILTRAIL. FULLSCREEN}
-->
</section>

<section>
	<title>Glide range</title>
<p>
A reachable glide footprint is displayed on the map display as a
dashed line, indicating where the glider would descend through the
terrain clearance height.  This footprint is calculated for tracks
extending 180 degrees around the glider.  The reachable glide
footprint is useful in assessing range with respect to topology when
searching low for lift, and when flying in mountainous areas.
</p>

<!-- XXX Image
\includegraphics[angle=0,width=0.5\linewidth,keepaspectratio='true']{cut-footprint.eps}
{\it DIAGRAM CUTOUT SHOWING GLIDE RANGE FOOTPRINT.  NO TOPOLOGY,
FULLSCREEN, NO TASK.}
-->

<p>
The final glide path is checked for whether the glider clears terrain
by the terrain clearance height.  If clearance is not attained, a red
cross appears on the map at the point where the violation occurs.
</p>

<!-- XXX Image
\includegraphics[angle=0,width=0.4\linewidth,keepaspectratio='true']{cut-fgtt.eps}
{\it DIAGRAM CUTOUT SHOWING FINAL GLIDE THROUGH TERRAIN WARNING
SYMBOL.  NO TOPOLOGY, FULLSCREEN, FINAL GLIDE TASK}
-->

</section>
</document>
