<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
        <metadata>
                <title></title>
        </metadata>

<section>
        <title>Indicators</title>
<p>
Indicators are icons drawn on the map area to indicate system status.
</p>

<section>
	<title>Flight modes</title>
<p>
	XCSoar automatically detects the difference between thermal (circling)
	flight and cruising flight. After about 30 seconds of circling flight
	the software will switch from cruise to climb mode. After about 30
	seconds of straight line flight the software will switch from climb to
	cruise mode.
</p>

<p>
	The cruise modes are further divided into final glide and normal
	cruise.  Final glide is active when the last waypoint in the task is
	active, or when the task is in abort mode.
</p>

<p>
	The symbols used to indicate these modes are shown below:
</p>

<ul>
	<li> Climb</li>
	<li> Cruise</li>
	<li> Final glide</li>
</ul>

<p>
	If there is no task active, then no flight mode symbol is shown.
</p>

<!-- XXX diagram 
{\it DIAGRAM CUTOUTS SHOWING FLIGHT MODE ICONS, NO TERRAIN/TOPOLOGY}
-->
</section>


<section>
	<title>GPS status</title>

<p>
	Normally, XCSoar requires a 3D GPS fix for its navigation functions.
	GPS status icons and text may appear on the bottom edge of the
	map display to indicate:
</p>

<dl>

	<dt>
		Waiting for GPS fix
	</dt>
	<dd>
		The GPS may have a 2D fix, better reception
		or additional time to search for satelites is required.
	</dd>

	<dt>
		GPS not connected
	</dt>
	<dd>
		No communication with the GPS is received.
		This indicates an error in the Comm port settings or the GPS device may
		be disconnected or switched off.
	</dd>

</dl>

<p>
When the GPS is not connected for more than one minute, XCSoar
automatically attempts to restart communication with the device and
will then resume waiting.  This method has shown to provide the most
reliable way of recovering from communication errors.
</p>

<!-- XXX Diagram
{\it DIAGRAM CUTOUT SHOWING GPS STATUS (SEVERAL DIAGRAMS EACH FOR DIFFERENT
 STATUS), NO TERRAIN/TOPOLOGY}
-->
</section>

<section>
	<title>Flight logger</title>

<p>
A flight logger conforming to the IGC file specification can be used
to record flights.  The logger can be turned on and off automatically
or manually.  When the logger is active, a small diamond in the lower
right corner of the map area flashes once per second.
</p>

<!-- XXX
{\it DIAGRAM CUTOUT SHOWING FLIGHT LOGGER ICON, NO TERRAIN/TOPOLOGY}
-->
</section>

</section>
</document>
