<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
        <metadata>
                <title>Documentation</title>
        </metadata>


		<section>
			<title>Documentation</title>

			<section>
				<title>When will there be documentation?</title> 
				<p>
				When will XCSoar support some better documentation?
				As soon as someone with the skill, resources, and time implements it.
				XCSoar isn't developed by a company. it's done
by <a href="/people/">volunteers</a>.
				Much of the development is done by people solving their own problems. 
				At this stage we have no one working on better
				documentation and we are in need of help.
				</p>

			</section>

			<section>
				<title>So what does it involve?</title>
				<p>
				Writing documentation for XCSoar does not
require any special computer skills. There is friendly developers on the 
<a href="https://sourceforge.net/mail/?group_id=141663">email list</a>
to answer any tricky quetsions, and there is someone to do all the
formatting and web work already (<a href="mailto:scottp@dd.com.au">Scott Penrose</a>). So you can do it in plain
text.
				</p>

				<p>
				Start by writing a short section and submitting
it to the developer list. Project like these work on a slow, incremental
process where you start with something small - get it out there for the users -
and progress from there. Not only is a small bit of work easier to manage and
complete, it is useful to others and even inspires more work from you and
others.
				</p>
			</section>
	
		</section>

		<section>
			<title>What right now?</title>
			<p>
			Have a look at the <a href="/install/">Installation</a>
section first, on how to download and install XCSoar on your computer. It
coveres the application well, however most map information has to be done by
hand.</p>
			<p>Move on to <a href="/quick/">Quick start</a> to give
you an overall view of what XCSoar does.</p>

			<p>From there, you are now in the more advanced
sections such as <a href="/infoboxes/">Info boxes</a>, <a
href="/settings/">Settings</a> and <a href="/input/">Input Control</a>.
			</p>

			<p>Good luck, and have fun.</p>

		</section>
</document>

