<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
        <metadata>
                <title>Warnings and Legal Notices</title>
        </metadata>

        <content>

                <section>
                        <title>Warnings and Precautions</title>
			<!-- XXX Fix the case on this sentence to be normal and
				use presentation rules for upper case -->

			IT IS THE USER'S RESPONSIBILITY TO USE THIS PRODUCT PRUDENTLY. THIS
			PRODUCT IS INTENDED TO BE USED ONLY AS A NAVIGATION AID AND MUST NOT
			BE USED FOR ANY PURPOSE REQUIRING PRECISE MEASUREMENT OF DIRECTION,
			DISTANCE, LOCATION, OR TOPOGRAPHY. THIS PRODUCT SHOULD NOT BE USED AS
			AN AID TO DETERMINE GROUND PROXIMITY FOR AIRCRAFT NAVIGATION.

		</section>
		

		<section>
			<title>Legal notices</title>

			<section>
				<title>Software license agreement</title>
				This software is released according to the GNU General Public License
				version 2.  See Appendix~\ref{cha:gnu-general-public} for the full
				text of the agreement and warranty notice.
			</section>

			<section>
				<title>Limited liability</title>
				In no event shall XCSoar, or its principals, shareholders, officers,
				employees, affiliates, contractors, subsidiaries, or parent
				organizations, be liable for any incidental, consequential, or
				punitive damages whatsoever relating to the use of the Product.
			</section>

			<section>
				<title>Disclaimer</title>
				Product, and all accompanying files, data and materials, are
				distributed "as is" and with no warranties of any kind, whether
				express or implied.  Product is used entirely at the risk of the
				user.  Although great care has been taken to eliminate defects during
				the development it is not claimed to be fault-free. No claims are made
				regarding its correctness, reliability or fitness for any particular
				purpose.  XCSoar shall not be liable for errors contained herein or for
				incidental or consequential damages, loss of data or personal injury
				in connection with furnishing, performance, or use of this material.

			</section>
		</section>
	</content>
</document>
