<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
        <metadata>
                <title>Quick start guide</title>
        </metadata>

        <content>

		<!-- XXX future update to use XML list of images -->

		<screenshots>

			<screenshot 
                                title="Hardware buttons in Map mode"
				src="fig-buttonsmap.png"
			>

The first user interface mode is Map mode, where the assignment of
buttons is primarily to control the display of map elements.  Map mode
can be selected at any time by touching the map area of the display.

			</screenshot>

			<screenshot 
				title="Hardware buttons in Infobox mode"
				src="fig-buttonsinfo.png"
			>

The second user interface mode is Infobox mode, where the assignment
of buttons is primarily to control the display of infoboxes and to set
user variables, such as MacReady settings, the active waypoint etc.
Infobox mode can be selected at any time by touching the infobox of
interest.  If an infobox is selected, the title turns grey, and it is
ready to accept user input.  The system reverts to Map mode after 10
seconds have elapsed with no key press.

Infobox types are described <a href="../infoboxes/index.html">here</a>.

			</screenshot>

			<screenshot 
                                title="Map display"
				src="fig-map.png"
			/>

			<screenshot 
                                title="Snail trail"
				src="fig-snail.png"
			/>

			<screenshot 
				title="Aborted task"
				src="fig-abort.png" 
			>

From the main menu, the task can be aborted if the pilot wishes to
terminate the task and find a safe landing point.  The task can later
be resumed if the pilot manages to climb away.  If there are reachable
landing points, these are sorted and fill the task waypoint list.  If
there are no reachable landing points, then the closest ten landing
points fill the task waypoint list.

			</screenshot>

			<screenshot 
				title="Auto MacReady"
				src="fig-automc.png"
			>

By selecting the MacReady infobox and pressing the hardware enter
button, Auto MacReady mode can be toggled. When the mode is active,
the MacReady setting is adjusted to result in fastest arrival on the
final glide slope.  If a supported intelligent variometer is connected
to XCSoar, its MacReady setting will also be automatically adjusted.

XCSoar has three flight modes: cruise, climb, and final glide.  The
flight modes switch automatically.  Infoboxes can be set up for each
flight mode independently, so the most relevant data to the user is
displayed.  A user option "Zoom circling" may be set to enable
automatic switching between long distance map scale when in
cruise/climb and a short distance map scale when circling.

			</screenshot>

			<screenshot 
                                title="Cruise flight mode"
				src="fig-task.png"
			>

Cruise flight mode is active when no waypoint is active, or when the
glider is cruising between waypoints prior to the final task waypoint.
When wind is present, it is indicated by red arrows pointing at the
glider, and the glider's approximate heading is represented by the
glider icon.  Several display orientations are available, such as
north-up and track-up.

A dashed green line represents the programmed task.
  
			</screenshot>

			<screenshot 
                                title="Flight director"
				src="fig-optcruise.png"
			>

In all flight modes, a solid black line is drawn from the glider to
target.  This is the shortest distance path between glider and target,
but it is not the optimal track bearing during cruise if wind is
present.  The optimal track bearing during cruise is indicated by the
solid blue arrow, and this is calculated to produce the minimum time
to target given that the glider will drift downwind when it stops to
circle.

			</screenshot>

			<screenshot 
				title="Climb flight mode"
				src="fig-climb.png"
			>

As the glider climbs, average climb rate statistics are collected and
displayed in a thermal profile chart, which may be useful in
determining the optimum working height band in cross-country tasks.
This chart is normalised by the current MacReady setting, which is
therefore easy to set to an appropriate value.  The glider's height
proportional to the thermal history is represented by the black arrow.

			</screenshot>

			<screenshot 
                                title="Final glide flight mode"
				src="fig-fglide.png"
			>

Final glide mode is very similar to cruise flight mode, except the
thermal profile is hidden, the mode has its own set of infoboxes, and
the computer assumes the glider is on a descent path to the target.

			</screenshot>

			<screenshot 
                                title="Glide through terrain"
				src="fig-fgtt.png"
			>

Final glide calculations check to determine whether the glide slope
takes the glider below a terrain safety height above the terrain
elevation.  If it does, a red cross appears on the map where the
intersection occurs.

			</screenshot>

			<screenshot 
                                title="Terrain safety heights"
				src="fig-terrain.png"
			>
			</screenshot>

			<screenshot 
                                title="Reachable glide"
				src="fig-foot.png"
			>
In all flight modes the glider's reach is calculated and displayed as
a dashed arc.  This line represents the location the glider would
intersect the terrain safety height above the terrain elevation, for a
180 degree sweep of bearing from the current glider's bearing.
			</screenshot>

			<screenshot 
                                title="Waypoint actions"
				src="CEZoom_WaypointActions.png"
			>
Waypoint details can be brought up by clicking on a waypoint on the
map display (zoom dependent), or if the waypoint is in the task, by selecting
the waypoint using the up/down arrow keys in the Next Waypoint infobox,
and pressing the enter key.

The waypoint details dialog has several pages.  This one, the waypoint
action page, allows adjustment of the task in flight etc.
			</screenshot>

			<screenshot 
                                title="Airfield data"
				src="fig-wpersa.png"
			>
Airfield data containing Enroute Supplement information is available
for major airfields.  The file format is very simple, allowing users
to edit their own entries for airfields.
			</screenshot>

			<screenshot 
                                title="Waypoint images"
				src="fig-wpmodis.png"
			>
Satelite images from MODIS can be brought up when a waypoint is selected.
This is useful prior to flight for the pilot to become familiar with the 
surroundings of the waypoints on task, or when landing out at another airfield.
Images for waypoints can be extracted from the waypoint file using
a script.  Automatic generation of these images will be supported via the XCSoar website at a later date.
			</screenshot>

<screenshot
  title="Menu"
  src="../settings/CEZoom_Menu.png"
>

Additional functionality is available from the XCSoar menu.  The menu
is activated by pressing the menu button which is made visible by
double tapping on the map display or by touching an infobox.

The following screenshots show the various pages that are activated
from the menu.  The settings page is described 
<a href="../settings/index.html"> here </a>.

</screenshot>

<screenshot
  title="Bugs and Ballast"
  src="../settings/CEZoom_BugsBallast.png"
>

This page allows entering the percent of permissible water ballast and
the degradation of performance (expressed as percent of ideal glide
angle) due to bugs.  This page can also be activated by pressing the
enter key on the "L/D" infobox.

</screenshot>

<screenshot
  title="Pressure"
  src="../settings/CEZoom_Pressure.png"
>

This page allows setting the field QNH, used in calibrating barometric
altimeters if installed, and in estimating altitude expressed as
Flight Level.  If a barometric altimeter is installed, the altitude is
displayed as the user adjusts the local pressure.

</screenshot>

<screenshot
  title="TaskPage"
  src="../settings/CEZoom_TaskPage.png"
>

Tasks may be defined by selecting waypoints on the list on the left,
and using the arrow buttons to add or remove them from the task.  Then
a task has more than three waypoints defined, it may also be set up as
an Assigned Area Task.  By selecting a task on the left and pressing
the details button, the waypoint details page is brought up.

When a supported logger is attached, the task may be declared to the
logger.

The following screenshots show settings available for AAT tasks.
</screenshot>

<screenshot
  title="TaskAATStart"
  src="../settings/CEZoom_TaskAATStart.png"
>
</screenshot>

<screenshot
  title="TaskAATSecond"
  src="../settings/CEZoom_TaskAATSecond.png"
>
</screenshot>

		</screenshots>



<!--

Introduction
This guide will help you get up and running with XCSoar, the Open Source soaring and navigation software for PDAs.
There are several steps involved. First you need to collect the required files. Then you'll need to  copy them to your PDA using ActiveSync. Finally, you'll want to customise XCSoar to your own requirements.
For detailed up-to-the-minute information about XCSoar, visit the web site at http://www.xcsoar.com.

Downloading the files you need
Main download page
Most of the files you need are available on the XCSoar Files page on SourceForge.net at this URL: http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=141663
XCSoar program
Download the file appropriate to your PDA from the Binaries section of the XCSoar Files page.
Language files
You can localise the text that XCSoar by downloading the appropriate language file from the XCSoar Files page. If your language is not yet listed, then please contact one of the XCSoar administrators who will gladly accept your offer to contribute a new set of translations!

Terrain and Topology
Download the Terrain and Topology package for your country from the Data section of the XCSoar Files page. If your country is not listed, please contact a member of the development team.
The terrain file is a mesh of the ground surface height above sea level. Even if you don't want to turn on the option to display this, XCSoar needs it to calculate and display your spot height above ground (QFE). This is a single file and is quite large (several MB).
The topology files contain data defining towns, roads, rail etc. XCSoar has an option switchable in flight to display this information on the moving map display. This is a collection of about 25 files in a subfolder of the Zip file.

Turning points
You will need to obtain a file for your country containing turning point information. This needs to be in Cambridge or Winpilot format (both are identical). You can get this from the Worldwide Soaring Turning Point Exchange at http://soaring.gahsys.com/TP/
Some countries have a file for the whole country plus regional sub-sets. If this is the case, go for the whole country file as XCSoar is not limited in the number of waypoints it can hold.

Airspace
You will also need the current airspace file for your country. This is available at the same location as the turning points and is listed under Special Use Airspace. You need to choose OpenAir format. Files for some areas may be available on the XCSoar site.
Synchronising with your PDA
You are probably familiar with the process of copying files from your PC to your PDA using Microsoft ActiveSync. Make a connection by placing the PDA in its cradle, then double-click on the XCSoar program image you downloaded. This will then be installed on your PDA.
Now copy the data files you downloaded to your PDA's My Documents folder on your PC. This will most likely be called Pocket_PC My Documents, unless you renamed your PDA. It's preferable to copy the topology files to a sub folder of MyDocuments (calling it Topo, for example) to avoid clutter in the PDA's main MyDocuments folder.
Setting up and Customising XCSoar
To set up XCSoar on your PDA, run the Simulator by tapping SIM on the Today screen. Settings are common between the Simulator and normal Flight mode. If you follow the instructions below in order, you will quickly have XCSoar up and running and ready to fly.

Initial Settings
Entering settings
Double-tap anywhere on the screen to bring up the Menu box. Tap this box to display the menu, then tap Settings.
Files
Select Core Files from the drop-down box. Tap the browse button next to Airspace file, and select the Airspace file that you downloaded. Repeat for the Waypoint file. Ignore the Additional file settings for now.
Now select Map Files from the drop-down box and browse for your Terrain and Topology files.
If you downloaded a Language file, select Interface Files from the drop-down box and browse for this file.
Now click ok to load all the files you selected so that you can use this information to make further settings.
Home Airfield
You may have noticed that when the files were loaded, the map is displayed centred on the first waypoint in the Waypoint file. To set your home airfield, bring up the Menu and tap the Task button. Choose your home airfield from the list on the left hand side and tap the Details... button. Now tap the >> button on the right, then the Set Home button, then Close.
For the new home airfield to take effect, you need to restart XCSoar. Bring up the Menu and tap Exit. Tap SIM on the Today screen and you should see the map displayed centred on your home airfield.
Other Settings

-->

	</content>
</document>

