<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
        <metadata>
                <title>Basic Operation</title>
        </metadata>

<section>
        <title>Basic Operation</title>


Basic operation

This chapter describes the fundamental user interface concepts used by
XCSoar, and is intended as an overview.  Specific button assignments,
menus and configuration settings are described in later chapters.

DIAGRAM SHOWING XCSOAR RUNNING ON PDA WITH BUTTONS. 
 }


The XCSoar display is composed of several parts:
\begin{description}
\item[Map area] The bulk of the screen is dedicated to the GPS moving 
 map display.
\item[Symbology] Glide computer information is overlaid on the map area.
\item[Gauges]  Gauges provide instrumentation displays
\item[Indicators] Icons and text may appear along the lower edge of
  the screen to indicate status of connected devices, flight modes etc.
\item[Status messages]  Text is displayed over the map area in status
 message boxes.  This text is used to present detailed information to
 the pilot when certain events occur. 
\item[InfoBoxes] A grid of data values is displayed either along
  the top and bottom of the screen (portrait display) 
  or to the right of the screen (landscape mode).  These InfoBoxes
  display data from the GPS and other input devices as well as
  data generated by the glide computer.  
\item[Dialog windows] Larger dialog windows, usually containing
  graphics and buttons, are used to present detailed data to the pilot
  regarding waypoint details, statistics and analysis etc. 
\item[Button labels and menus] Hardware buttons on the Pocket PC
  can be used to bring up and navigate smaller onscreen menus that
  are typically laid out such that menu items can be selected by pressing
  the button adjacent to the item.  If the Pocket PC has a touch screen,
  then menu items can be selected by touching them.
\item[Main menu] The main menu is accessible by touching the map area,
  which brings up a ``Menu'' button, which then if touched brings up
  a full-page dialog containing the main menu items.  If the Menu button
  is not pressed after more than 10 seconds, it disappears again so as to
  not obscure the map area.
\end{description}

There are several ways in which the pilot can interact with XCSoar:
\begin{itemize}
\item Touching certain map elements
\item Touching infoboxes and onscreen buttons
\item `Dragging' the screen (touching the screen and moving before releasing)
\item Pressing application buttons on the Pocket PC device.
\item Pressing the cursor keys on the Pocket PC device.
\item Pressing keys or switches on an instrument connected to XCSoar.
\end{itemize}
Depending on the particular hardware used with XCSoar, not all of
these methods of interaction are possible, and there may be different
numbers or assignments of buttons.  Refer to
Chapter~\ref{cha:hardware} for details of major hardware
configurations.


</section>
</document>
