<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
        <metadata>
                <title>Infobox Descriptions</title>
        </metadata>

        <content>

<section>
	<title>Info Boxes</title>

	<p>
	Infobox data types are grouped into logical categories.  The type of a
	particular infobox may be cycled through each type within its category
	by pressing the application buttons 2 and 3 when the infobox is
	highlighted.
	</p>

	<p>
	All infoboxes display their data in user-specified units.  Where data
	is invalid, the displayed value will be '---'.  This happens, for
	example, when no terrain data is found or in range for the Terrain
	Elevation infobox type.
	</p>

	<p>
	In the following description of the infobox data types, the first
	title is as it appears in the infobox configuration dialog box, the
	second title is the label used in the infobox title.  Note that these
	labels have changed since older versions (pre V4.2) of XCSoar.
	</p>

	<section>
		<title>Altitude group</title>

		<dl>
			<dt>Height GPS: H GPS</dt>
			<dd>
				This is the height above mean sea level reported by the GPS.
				In simulation mode, this value is adjustable with the up/down arrow keys.
				When this infobox is active, the right/left arrow keys also cause the
				glider to turn.
			</dd>

			<dt>Height AGL: H AGL</dt>
			<dd>
				This is the GPS altitude minus the terrain height obtained from the
				terrain file.  The value is colored red when the glider is below the
				terrain safety clearance height.
			</dd>
			 
			<dt>Terrain Elevation: H Gnd</dt>
			<dd>
				This is the elevation of the terrain above mean sea level obtained 
				from the terrain file.
			</dd>

			<dt>Pressure Altitude: H Baro</dt>
			<dd>
				This is the barometric altitude obtained from a GPS equipped with
				pressure sensor, or a supported external intelligent vario.
			</dd>

		</dl>
	</section>

	<section>
		<title>Aircraft state group</title>
		<dl>
			<dt>Bearing: Bearing</dt>
			<dd>
				True bearing of the next waypoint.
			</dd>

			<dt>Speed ground: V Gnd</dt>
			<dd>
				Ground speed measured by the GPS.
				If this infobox is active in simulation mode, pressing the up and down
				arrows adjusts the speed, and left and right turn the glider.
			</dd>

			<dt>Track: Track</dt>
			<dd>
				Magnetic track reported by the GPS.
				If this infobox is active in simulation mode, pressing the up and down
				arrows adjusts the track.
			</dd>

			<dt>Airspeed IAS: V IAS</dt>
			<dd>
				Indicated Airspeed reported by a supported external intelligent
				vario.
			</dd>

			<dt>G load: G</dt>
			<dd>
			Magnitude of G loading reported by a supported external intelligent
			vario.  This value is negative for pitch-down manoeuvers.
			</dd>
		</dl>
	</section>

	<section>

		<title>Glide ratio group</title>
		<dl>
			<dt>L/D instantaneous: L/D Inst</dt>
			<dd>
				Instantaneous glide ratio, given by the ground speed divided by the
				vertical speed.  Negative values indicate climbing cruise.  If the vertical
				speed is close to zero, the displayed value is '---'.
				If this infobox is active, pressing the enter cursor button brings up the
				bugs and ballast dialog.
				</dd>

			<dt>L/D cruise: L/D Cru</dt>
			<dd>
				The distance from the top of the last thermal, divided by the altitude
				lost since the top of the last thermal.  Negative values indicate
				climbing cruise (height gain since leaving the last thermal).  If the
				vertical speed is close to zero, the displayed value is '---'.
			</dd> 

			<dt>Final L/D: Fin L/D</dt>
			<dd>
				The required glide ratio to finish the task, given by the distance to
				go divided by the height required to arrive at the safety arrival
				altitude.  Negative values indicate a climb is necessary to finish.
				If the height required is close to zero, the displayed value is '---'.
			</dd>

			<dt>Next L/D: WP L/D</dt>
			<dd>
				The required glide ratio to reach the next waypoint, given by the
				distance to next waypoint divided by the height required to arrive at
				the safety arrival altitude.  Negative values indicate a climb is
				necessary to reach the waypoint.  If the height required is close to
				zero, the displayed value is '---'.
			</dd>

		</dl>
	</section>

	<section>
		<title>Variometer group</title>

		<dl>
			<dt>Thermal last 30 sec: TC 30s</dt>
			<dd>
				A 30 second rolling average climb rate based of the reported GPS altitude.
			</dd>

			<dt>Last Thermal Average: TL Avg</dt>
			<dd>
				Total altitude gain/loss in the last thermal divided by the time spent circling.
			</dd>
			 
			<dt>Last Thermal Gain: TL Gain</dt>
			<dd>
				Total altitude gain/loss in the last thermal.
			</dd>
 
			<dt>Last Thermal Time: TL Time</dt>
			<dd>
				Time spent circling in the last thermal.
			</dd>

			<dt>Thermal Average: TC Avg</dt>
			<dd>
				Altitude gained/lost in the current thermal, divided by time spent thermaling.
			</dd>

			<dt>Thermal Gain: TC Gain</dt>
			<dd>
				The altitude gained/lost in the current thermal.
			</dd>

			<dt>Vario: Vario</dt>
			<dd>
				Instantaneous vertical speed, as reported by the GPS, or the intelligent
				vario total energy vario value if connnected to one.
			</dd>

		</dl>
	</section>

	<section>

		<title>Wind group</title>
		<dl>
			<dt>Wind Speed: Wind V</dt>
			<dd>
				Wind speed estimated by XCSoar.  Manual adjustment is possible
				by pressing the up/down cursor keys to adjust magnitude and left/right
				cursor keys to adjust bearing when the infobox is active.  Pressing the
				enter cursor key saves the wind value as the initial value when XCSoar next
				starts.
			</dd>

			<dt> Wind Bearing: Wind B</dt>
			<dd>
				Wind bearing estimated by XCSoar.  Manual adjustment is possible by
				pressing the up/down cursor keys to adjust bearing when the infobox is
				active.
			</dd>

		</dl>
	</section>

	<section>
		<title>McCready group</title>

		<dl>
			<dt>McCready Setting: McCready</dt>
			<dd>
				The current McCready setting. Also used to adjust the McCready Setting if
				the infobox is active, by using the up/down cursor keys.  Pressing the
				enter cursor key toggles AutoMcCready mode.
			</dd>

			<dt>Speed McCready: V Mc</dt>
			<dd>
				The McCready speed-to-fly.  In cruise flight mode, this speed-to-fly
				is calculated for maintaining altitude.  In final glide mode, this
				speed-to-fly is calculated for descent.
			</dd>

			<dt>Percentage climb: % Climb</dt>
			<dd>
				Percentage of time spent in climb mode
			</dd>
		</dl>
	</section>

	<section>

		<title>Navigation group</title>

		<dl>
			<dt>Next Distance: WP Dist</dt>
			<dd>
				The distance to the currently selected waypoint.
			</dd> 

			<dt>Next Altitude Difference: WP AltD</dt>
			<dd>
				Arrival altitude at the next waypoint relative to
				the safety arrival altitude.
			</dd>
			 
			<dt>Next Altitude Required: WP AltR</dt>
			<dd>
				Altitude required to reach the next turn point.
			</dd>
			 
			<dt>Final Altitude Difference: Fin AltD</dt>
			<dd>
				Arrival altitude at the final task turn point relative to
				the safety arrival altitude.
			</dd>
			 
			<dt>Final Altitude Required: Fin AltR</dt>
			<dd>
				Altitude required to finish the task. 
			</dd>

			<dt>Speed Task Average: V Task</dt>
			<dd>
				Average cross country speed while on current task.
			</dd>
 
			<dt>Final Distance: Fin Dis</dt>
			<dd>Distance to finish around remaining turn points.</dd>
			 
			<dt>AA Time: AA Time</dt>
			<dd>(TBD)</dd>

			<dt>AA Distance Max: AA Dmax</dt>
			<dd>(TBD)</dd>

			<dt>AA Distance Min: AA Dmin</dt>
			<dd>(TBD)</dd>

			<dt>AA Speed Max: AA Vmax</dt>
			<dd>(TBD)</dd>

			<dt>AA Speed Min: AA Vmin</dt>
			<dd>(TBD)</dd>

		</dl>

	</section>

	<section>

		<title>Waypoint group</title>
		<dl>
			<dt>Next Waypoint: Next</dt>
			<dd>
				The name of the currently selected turn point.  When this infobox is active, using the up/down cursor keys selects the next/previous waypoint in the task.
				Pressing the enter cursor key brings up the waypoint details.
			</dd>
			 
			<dt>Time of flight: Time flt</dt>
			<dd>Time elapsed since the GPS detected speed greater than 5 knots.</dd>

			<dt>Time local: Time loc</dt>
			<dd>GPS time expressed in local time zone.</dd>

			<dt>Time UTC: Time UTC</dt>
			<dd>GPS time expressed in UTC.</dd>

		</dl>
	</section>

</section>
</content>
</document>
     
 
