<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
        <metadata>
                <title>Symbology</title>
        </metadata>

<section>
        <title>Symbology</title>

<p>
Symbology refers to icons and other graphics overlaid on the map area
but which are not specifically map objects.
</p>

<p>
A north arrow is displayed on the top right corner of the map display.
</p>

<section>
	<title>Wind</title>

<p>
A continuous display of wind strength and direction is provided. The
wind information is derived from the gliders wind drift during thermal
flight (climb mode). 
</p>

<p>
The wind direction and speed are displayed as a
wind vector on the moving map display and optionally in numeric form in
the data display fields.  The length of the vector indicates the wind
magnitude, and this magnitude is also displayed near the wind vector.
</p>

<p>
The wind data is one of many data sources used to calculate final
glide information.  It is possible to manually adjust the wind used in
all calculations.
</p>

<!-- XXX Image
\includegraphics[angle=0,width=0.15\linewidth,keepaspectratio='true']{cut-windarrow.eps}
{\it DIAGRAM CUTOUT SHOWING WIND VECTOR AT GLIDER, MAYBE ALSO SHOW A
WINDSOCK NEXT TO THE DISPLAY TO MAKE THE DIRECTION OBVIOUS.  NO
TERRAIN/TOPOLOGY}
-->

</section>

<section>
	<title>Altitude required</title>

<p>
On the left side of the map display, a box displays the calculated
height difference required for the glider to complete the task, or
reach the final waypoint.  If the glider is above the minimum height
required, a green arrow bar is drawn above the box indicating the
amount of excess height.  If the glider is below the minimum height
required, a red arrow bar is drawn below the box indicating the amount
of height deficit.
</p>

<!--
\includegraphics[angle=0,width=0.15\linewidth,keepaspectratio='true']{cut-fg-above.eps}
\includegraphics[angle=0,width=0.2\linewidth,keepaspectratio='true']{cut-fg-below.eps}
{\it DIAGRAM CUTOUT SHOWING ALTITUDE REQUIRED ARROW AND TEXT.  TWO
DIAGRAMS, ONE A LOT BELOW, ONE A LITTLE ABOVE.  NO TERRAIN/TOPOLOGY}
-->

</section>

<section>
	<title>Speed command chevrons</title>

<p>
When used in conjunction with an intelligent variometer that produces
indicated airspeed measurements, then a speed command chevron is drawn
on the right side of the map display.  If the glider is flying slower
than the optimal speed, the chevrons are red and point downwards.  If
the glider is flying faster than the optimal speed, the chevrons are
green and point upwards.  If the speed is approximately optimal, no
chevrons are drawn.
</p>

<!-- XXX Image
%\includegraphics[angle=0,width=0.8\linewidth,keepaspectratio='true']{../quick/fig-fglide.eps}
{\it DIAGRAM CUTOUT SHOWING SPEED COMMAND CHEVRONS.  TWO DIAGRAMS, ONE
A LOT TOO SLOW, ONE A LITTLE TOO FAST.  NO TERRAIN/TOPOLOGY.}
-->

</section>

<section>
	<title>Optimal cruise track</title>

<p>
The glide computer accounts for wind drift during circling to provide
an 'optimal cruise track' vector, which indicates the track the glider
should follow during cruise such that it will arrive at the waypoint
in minimum time.  This vector is displayed on the map as a blue arrow.
When wind is negligable, or in final glide mode, this arrow will point
along the black line that indicates the track to the next waypoint.
</p>

<!--
\includegraphics[angle=0,width=0.8\linewidth,keepaspectratio='true']{../quick/fig-optcruise.eps}
{\it DIAGRAM CUTOUT SHOWING OPTIMAL CRUISE TRACK.  NO
TERRAIN/TOPOLOGY.  MAYBE SHOW A DRIFTING/CRUISING GLIDER NEXT TO
DIAGRAM.}
-->

</section>

<section>
	<title>Thermal profile</title>

<p>
Statistics on climb rates in thermals are collected and displayed in a
thermal band meter.  This is shown above the final glide difference
bar on the left side of the map display.  It is not shown when the
glider is above final glide.
</p>

<!--
\includegraphics[angle=0,width=\linewidth,keepaspectratio='true']{../quick/fig-climb.eps}
{\it DIAGRAM CUTOUT SHOWING THERMAL PROFILE, AFTER THERMALLING, WITH
MC SET.  NO TERRAIN/TOPOLOGY.  LABELED ARROW POINT TO HEIGHT/MC
ARROW.}
-->

<p>
The thermal band meter shows a graph, where the vertical axis is
height above the break-off height and is scaled according to the
maximum height achieved.  The horizontal axis is the average climb
rate achieved at a particular height band.  The horizontal axis is
scaled according to the MacReady setting, and an arrow indicating this
setting and the glider's current height is overlaid on the shaded
area.  This scaling and arrow makes it easy to see how the pilot's
MacReady setting compares with achieved thermals and to plan the
desired working height band.
</p>

</section>

</section>
</document>
